<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fact-checking on CopeNLU</title>
    <link>https://copenlu.github.io/tags/fact-checking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fact-checking on CopeNLU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copenlu.github.io/tags/fact-checking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Papers Accepted to AAAI 2022</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2021_12_aaai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2021_12_aaai/</guid>
      <description>2 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at AAAI 2022. One paper is on explanation generation, demonstrating how directly optimising for diagnostic properties of explanations, such as faithfulness, data consistency and confidence indication, can improve explanation quality. The other paper presents the most comprehensive study of cross-lingual stance detection to date, and proposes methods for learning with limited labelled data across languages and domains.
Diagnostics-Guided Explanation Generation. Pepa Atanasova, Jakob Grue Simonsen, Christina Lioma, Isabelle Augenstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Accepted to IJCAI 2021</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2021_04_ijcai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2021_04_ijcai/</guid>
      <description>A paper by CopeNLU author is accepted to appear at IJCAI 2021. The paper studies how to perform complex claim verification on naturally occurring political claims with multiple hops over evidence chunks.
Multi-Hop Fact Checking of Political Claims. Wojciech Ostrowski, Arnav Arora, Pepa Atanasova, Isabelle Augenstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stance Detection and Fact Checking</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/project/fact-checking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/project/fact-checking/</guid>
      <description>We are interested in studying method to determine the attitude expressed in a text towards a topic (stance detection), such as determining if a tweet expresses a positive, negative or neutral stance towards a political entity. One additional challenge we are exploring is stance detection in a conversational context, where the stance depends on the context of the conversation. Fact checking using textual data can be framed very similarly, namely as if an evidence document agrees with, disagrees with or is topically unrelated to a headline or claim.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Papers Accepted to ACL 2020</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2020_04_acl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2020_04_acl/</guid>
      <description>2 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at ACL 2020. One paper is on explainable fact checking, providing the first study of how fact checking explanations can be generated automatically based on claim content, and how this task can be modelled jointly with veracity prediction; whereas the other one is on script conversion, proposing a novel Chinese character conversion model that can disambiguate between mappings and convert between Chinese scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>