<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lld on CopeNLU</title>
    <link>https://copenlu.github.io/tags/lld/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lld on CopeNLU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copenlu.github.io/tags/lld/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning with Limited Labelled Data</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/project/limited-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/project/limited-data/</guid>
      <description>Learning with limited labelled data is useful for small domains or languages with little resources. Methods we research to mitigate problems arising in these contexts include multi-task learning, weakly supervised and zero-shot learning.
This is a cross-cutting theme in most of our research. Two funded projects specifically addressing this are Multi3Generation and Andreas Nugaard Holm&amp;rsquo;s industrial PhD project with BASE Life Science, supported by Innovation Fund Denmark.
Multi3Generation is a COST Action that funds collaboration of researchers in Europe and abroad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilingual Learning</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/project/multilingual-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/project/multilingual-learning/</guid>
      <description>Multi-lingual learning is concerned with training models to work well for multiple languages, including low-resource ones. We research methods for enabling information sharing between multiple languages, and also study how to utilise typological knowledge bases to this end. We are currently involved in three larger funded projects on this.
Multi3Generation is a COST Action that funds collaboration of researchers in Europe and abroad. The project is coordinated by Isabelle Augenstein, and its goals are to study language generation using multi-task, multilingual and multi-modal signals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>