<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on CopeNLU</title>
    <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on CopeNLU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copenlu.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Papers Accepted to ACL 2020</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2020_04_acl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2020_04_acl/</guid>
      <description>2 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at ACL 2019. One paper is on explainable fact checking, providing the first study of how fact checking explanations can be generated automatically based on claim content, and how this task can be modelled jointly with veracity prediction; whereas the other one is on script conversion, proposing a novel Chinese character conversion model that can disambiguate between mappings and convert between Chinese scripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 papers to be presented at EMNLP 2019</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_11_emnlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_11_emnlp/</guid>
      <description>4 papers by CopeNLU authors are to be presented at EMNLP 2019 and co-located events, on fact checking and disinformation, as well as on multi-task and multi-lingual learning.
MultiFC: A Real-World Multi-Domain Dataset for Evidence-Based Fact Checking of Claims. Isabelle Augenstein, Christina Lioma, Dongsheng Wang, Lucas Chaves Lima, Casper Hansen, Christian Hansen, Jakob Grue Simonsen. In Proceedings of EMNLP-IJCNLP 2019.
Mapping (Dis-)Information Flow about the MH17 Plane Crash. Mareike Hartmann, Yevgeniy Golovchenko, Isabelle Augenstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Papers Accepted to ACL 2019</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_05_acl/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_05_acl/</guid>
      <description>2 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at ACL 2019. One paper is on uncovering probabilistic implications in typological knowledge bases, following up from our NAACL 2019 paper on generative linguistic typology; whereas the other one is on unsupervised discovery of gendered language, utilising the multi-view autoencoder introduced in our NAACL 219 paper.
Uncovering Probabilistic Implications in Typological Knowledge Bases. Johannes Bjerva, Yova Kementchedjhieva, Ryan Cotterell, Isabelle Augenstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Papers Accepted to NAACL 2019</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_02_naacl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_02_naacl/</guid>
      <description>3 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at NAACL 2019. Topics span from population of typological knowledge bases and weak supervision from disparate lexica to frame detection in online fora.
A Probabilistic Generative Model of Linguistic Typology. Johannes Bjerva, Yova Kementchedjhieva, Ryan Cotterell, Isabelle Augenstein.
Combining Disparate Sentiment Lexica with a Multi-View Variational Autoencoder. Alexander Hoyle, Lawrence Wolf-Sonkin, Hanna Wallach, Ryan Cotterell, Isabelle Augenstein.
Issue Framing in Online Discussion Fora.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>