<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on CopeNLU</title>
    <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on CopeNLU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copenlu.github.io/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Papers Accepted to NAACL 2019</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_02_naacl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_02_naacl/</guid>
      <description>3 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at NAACL 2019. Topics span from population of typological knowledge bases and weak supervision from disparate lexica to frame detection in online fora.
A Probabilistic Generative Model of Linguistic Typology. Johannes Bjerva, Yova Kementchedjhieva, Ryan Cotterell, Isabelle Augenstein.
Combining Disparate Sentiment Lexica with a Multi-View Variational Autoencoder. Alexander Hoyle, Lawrence Wolf-Sonkin, Hanna Wallach, Ryan Cotterell, Isabelle Augenstein.
Issue Framing in Online Discussion Fora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>35 Marie Skłodowska-Curie PhD Fellowships Available</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_02_phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2019_02_phd/</guid>
      <description>35 Marie Skłodowska-Curie PhD fellowships are available at the University of Copenhagen Faculty of Science via the TALENT program. The fellowship offers applicants employment as PhD fellows for a period of three years on a research topic of the fellow&amp;rsquo;s choice. The current call is open from 15 February to 1 April 2019 for a start date in Autumn 2019. Candidates are required to have completed a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree at the time of application, to not have resided in Denmark in the past 12 months, and to have a recent English language certificate.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>