<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on CopeNLU</title>
    <link>https://copenlu.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on CopeNLU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copenlu.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ALPS 2021 tutorial &#39;Explainability for NLP&#39;</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/post/explainability_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/post/explainability_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>We gave a tutorial on &amp;lsquo;Explainability for NLP&amp;rsquo; at the first ALPS (Advanced Language Processing) winter school: http://lig-alps.imag.fr/index.php/schedule/ The tutorial introduces the concepts of &amp;lsquo;model understanding&amp;rsquo; as well as &amp;lsquo;decision understanding&amp;rsquo; and provides examples of approaches from the areas of fact checking and text classification.
Exercises for both model understanding and decision understanding are available here: https://github.com/copenlu/ALPS_2021</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EMNLP 2020 Beer Garden Meetup</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/post/eth-ucph-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/post/eth-ucph-party/</guid>
      <description>Yes, we all have planned to be under palm trees of Punta Cana now and to sip drinks with umbrellas. Let&amp;rsquo;s make a new plan: beer garden on Thursday evening (19:30 CET). All ETH Rycolab and UCPH CopeNLU research group members &amp;amp; friends are invited to join our Gather.Town beer garden to mingle with one another. Sign up here to get the invitation link. The number of spots is limited!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interested in joining us at the University of Copenhagen?</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/post/why-ucph/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/post/why-ucph/</guid>
      <description>The University of Copenhagen is a great place if you&amp;rsquo;re both interested in high-quality NLP research (we&amp;rsquo;re ranked 2nd in Europe and 19th in the world on CSRankings for NLP) and a high quality of life (Denmark has consistently been ranked one of the three happiest countries in the world, and ranks equally highly on the quality of life). In addition to this, Copenhagen is a lively, bustling capital, while still being small enough that one can cycle nearly everwhere within a short amount of time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>