<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>knowledge-bases on CopeNLU</title>
    <link>https://copenlu.github.io/tags/knowledge-bases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in knowledge-bases on CopeNLU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copenlu.github.io/tags/knowledge-bases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Papers Accepted to ACL 2023</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2023_05_acl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2023_05_acl/</guid>
      <description>4 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at ACL 2023. The papers make contributions within faithfulness of explanations, measuring intersectional biases, event extraction and few-shot stance detection.
Topic-Guided Sampling For Data-Efficient Multi-Domain Stance Detection. Erik Arakelyan, Arnav Arora, Isabelle Augenstein.
Faithfulness Tests for Natural Language Explanations. Pepa Atanasova, Oana-Maria Camburu, Christina Lioma, Thomas Lukasiewicz, Jakob Grue Simonsen, Isabelle Augenstein.
Measuring Intersectional Biases in Historical Documents. Nadav Borenstein, Karolina Stańczak, Thea Rolskov, Natacha Klein Käfer, Natália da Silva Perez, Isabelle Augenstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge Base Population</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/project/knowledge-bases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/project/knowledge-bases/</guid>
      <description>Information extraction is concerned with extracting information about entities, phrases and relations between them from text to populate knowledge bases, such as extracting &amp;ldquo;employee-at&amp;rdquo; relations. Within this context, we have worked on automatic knowledge base completion, knowledge base cleansing and detecting scientific keyphrases in text, as well as automatic completion of typological knowledge bases.
We are currently involved in one longer-term project related to this, namely a research project funded by the Swedish Research Council coordinated by Robert Östling.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>