<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>question-answering on CopeNLU</title>
    <link>https://copenlu.github.io/tags/question-answering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in question-answering on CopeNLU</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://copenlu.github.io/tags/question-answering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Papers Accepted to ACL 2023</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2023_05_acl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2023_05_acl/</guid>
      <description>4 papers by CopeNLU authors are accepted to appear at ACL 2023. The papers make contributions within faithfulness of explanations, measuring intersectional biases, event extraction and few-shot stance detection.
Topic-Guided Sampling For Data-Efficient Multi-Domain Stance Detection. Erik Arakelyan, Arnav Arora, Isabelle Augenstein.
Faithfulness Tests for Natural Language Explanations. Pepa Atanasova, Oana-Maria Camburu, Christina Lioma, Thomas Lukasiewicz, Jakob Grue Simonsen, Isabelle Augenstein.
Measuring Intersectional Biases in Historical Documents. Nadav Borenstein, Karolina Stańczak, Thea Rolskov, Natacha Klein Käfer, Natália da Silva Perez, Isabelle Augenstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Papers Accepted to Coling 2022</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2022_08_coling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/talk/2022_08_coling/</guid>
      <description>2 papers by CopeNLU authors on probing question answering models are accepted to appear at Coling 2022.
Machine Reading, Fast and Slow: When Do Models &amp;lsquo;Understand&amp;rsquo; Language?. Sagnik Ray Choudhury, Anna Rogers, Isabelle Augenstein.
Can Edge Probing Tasks Reveal Linguistic Knowledge in QA Models?. Sagnik Ray Choudhury, Nikita Bhutani, Isabelle Augenstein.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Question Answering</title>
      <link>https://copenlu.github.io/project/question-answering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://copenlu.github.io/project/question-answering/</guid>
      <description>Question answering is concerned with answer user questions, either in a closed-domain or open-domain setting automatically. We are interested in exploiting synergies between question answering and related tasks, such as framing entailment or relation extraction as question answering tasks. Further research interests are question answering in conversational settings, such as for chatbots.
We are currently involved in two funded projects related to this theme: a project on subjectivity in question answering, funded by a faculty research award from Megagon Labs; as well a PhD fellowship grant on conversational question answering for customer support from BotXO, which Ana Valeria Gonzalez works on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>